On May 7th, President Xi left Beijing to visit Russia. This visit to Russia has two main purposes.
One is to promote bilateral relations. Another significant theme is to commemorate the 80th anniversary of the Great Patriotic War.
The Russian government has announced that President Putin will visit China at the end of August.
He will participate in the activities commemorating the 80th anniversary of the victory in the War of Resistance against Japan on September 3rd.
So, a major theme this year is to reaffirm the correct historical perspective on World War II.
After the Cold War, with the dissolution of the Soviet Union, the West not only physically eliminated the Soviet Union but also psychologically erased its traces.
After more than thirty years of Western propaganda,
many Europeans now
seem to have forgotten that it was the Soviet Red Army that liberated Europe.
A typical example is a public opinion survey in France. In the 1950s, the French people certainly acknowledged the contributions of the Soviet Red Army.
Now, it seems like everyone thinks it was the United States that defeated Nazi Germany.
Under King Yu of the Qi State, he actually...
wants to completely erase this history. This is one situation. So under these circumstances, it's important to uphold the correct view of World War II history.
This is very important. China was actually the main battlefield in Asia during World War II, just as the Soviet Union was the main battlefield in Europe.
But now, in Western discourse, it's gradually...
starting to downplay China's importance and also diminish the role of the Soviet Union. Both sides now have common interests and must uphold the correct view of World War II history.
These issues are tied to current interests. If...
the view of World War II history is overturned, and the historical and legal legitimacy of the Potsdam Declaration is challenged...
Well, many of those...
actions that disrupt the post-World War II order will start to emerge.
Including many Eastern European countries now, right? They completely deny the role of the Soviet Red Army and the sacrifices of the Soviet Union. And on our side,
it begins.
The practical consequence is the denial of the Party's multiple announcements and the order of World War II.
Well, he might.
Just deny the legitimacy of the country.
And now, it seems that some Americans, some scholars, and later, under the influence of a certain CA,
start to deny.
Resolution 2758.
It has practical significance, right?
So adhering to the correct historical view of World War II and the international order represented by the United Nations after the war is in the interests of both countries now.
This year, both countries have placed special emphasis on the 80th anniversary of the victory in World War II. One way to show this importance is through military parades.
And of course, this action is much more significant.
It's far more important than small academic seminars or similar events.
Right? Of course, we scholars also need to actively voice our opinions.
We scholars must stand firm on our national stance and not be swayed.
We shouldn't be misled by the American rhetoric. Indeed, the impact of this parade.
I estimate that this parade.
Its impact might surpass many student seminars, you know? This is probably the primary reason President Xi attended.
The second reason, of course, is to strengthen Sino-Russian relations. The world today is very turbulent, and.
The United States is currently relying on its hegemony.
They are just bullying people more and more.
So.
Under these circumstances, well, this, this.
Actually, China's interests are being harmed, and so is the world order.
Under these circumstances.
The relationship between China and Russia is very important, just like Foreign Minister Wang Yi mentioned on March 7th.
At the press conference, he said.
In today's world, changes and warming are intertwined, and it's very uncertain.
China is a relatively stable factor, and the China-Russia relationship is even more stable. Strengthening the China-Russia relationship is particularly important for the stability of the whole world.
In.
Specifically applied to Chinese diplomacy, everyone knows that since Trump took office, he has had the idea of allying with Russia to contain China, right?
It seems he doesn't shy away from it; he just mentioned it publicly, though not as explicitly as in his first term.
In his first term, his strategist, Bannon, Stephen Bannon, was quite open about it.
It was publicly stated that the characteristic of Trump's administration's foreign policy is primarily about two enforcements.
Although, logically speaking, joint enforcement is challenging.
In reality, it's quite difficult to achieve.
But in any case, China is making some efforts, right?
We are making efforts to stabilize Sino-Russian relations.
Specifically, in the context of the U.S. wanting to enforce jointly, we aim to strengthen Sino-Russian relations to thwart that idea.
Lastly, it's about solving some specific issues. Sino-European relations are generally stable, but there are still many difficulties within.
Ah, we need to address this issue, for example.
For instance, the trade relations between China and Russia are very good, but now.
Friends involved in trade with China are facing a problem, which is the payment between both sides.
Now there is an issue, right? This requires both sides to find a solution together.
Our goods have been sold there and are very popular.
But the money can't come back.
So this has caused difficulties for subsequent trade, right? Additionally, Russia still has some.
This, this.
Some ideas that we find somewhat abnormal, for example, Russian customs.
Often, they are quite strict with Chinese people, right? And they are also strict with Chinese companies.
So.
This should be discussed.
This has caused some unpleasant feelings among the people, right?
Therefore.
Hmm.
Through the summit meeting, right? To establish some basic principles.
Uh, to eliminate some.
Specific obstacles in Sino-Russian relations, right? This should also be one of the goals.
We believe that through President Xi's visit, Sino-Russian relations in the near future.
Will be relatively stable, maintaining stability is something we can expect.